<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog</id>
    <title>Piotr Kmita Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-10-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Piotr Kmita Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/img/pk.svg</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Console-to-Code Service for Amazon AWS]]></title>
        <id>https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-console-to-code</id>
        <link href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-console-to-code"/>
        <updated>2024-10-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AWS has introduced the Console-to-Code service, which allows users to easily convert actions performed in the AWS console into code, greatly simplifying the process of automation and application deployment. Here’s how the service works and how you can use it.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>AWS has introduced the <strong>Console-to-Code</strong> service, which allows users to easily convert actions performed in the AWS console into code, greatly simplifying the process of automation and application deployment. Here’s how the service works and how you can use it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-does-console-to-code-work">How Does Console-to-Code Work?<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-console-to-code#how-does-console-to-code-work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do How Does Console-to-Code Work?" title="Bezpośredni link do How Does Console-to-Code Work?">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Action Recording</strong>: Console-to-Code automatically records all user actions in the AWS console, such as creating EC2 instances or configuring VPCs. The user performs standard operations in the console, and the system logs these actions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Code Generation</strong>: Once the actions are completed, the user can go to the Console-to-Code panel and select specific actions to convert into code. The service generates code in the preferred format, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>AWS CloudFormation</strong> (JSON or YAML)</li>
<li><strong>AWS CDK</strong> (Java, Python, TypeScript)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>However, you need to enable recording first by clicking "Start recording".</strong><br>
<!-- -->Below is an example of what it looks like when using the EC2 service:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="alt text" src="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/assets/images/ConsoleToCode-63aa130b3160cd5a3e9da38d770364c8.png" title="ConsoleToCode" width="3795" height="1325" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Code Customization</strong>: The generated code can serve as a starting point for further customization to meet specific production needs. Users are encouraged to test and verify the generated code before deployment.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-to-use-console-to-code">How to Use Console-to-Code?<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-console-to-code#how-to-use-console-to-code" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do How to Use Console-to-Code?" title="Bezpośredni link do How to Use Console-to-Code?">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-by-step">Step-by-Step:<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-console-to-code#step-by-step" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do Step-by-Step:" title="Bezpośredni link do Step-by-Step:">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Log in to the AWS console</strong>: Make sure you're in the <strong>US East (N. Virginia)</strong> region, as this is a fairly new service and may not be available in all regions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Open the Console-to-Code Panel</strong>: Start the recording process by clicking "Start recording". You can find Console-to-Code in the top right corner.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Select the EC2 Service</strong>: Begin the process, for example, by launching an EC2 instance.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Choose Actions to Convert</strong>: Select the actions you want to include in the generated code (up to 5 actions at a time).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Generate Code</strong>: Click the generate code button and choose the preferred format.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Download or Copy Code</strong>: After the code is generated, you can either copy or download it for further editing.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="limitations">Limitations<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-console-to-code#limitations" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do Limitations" title="Bezpośredni link do Limitations">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The service is currently available only for actions related to Amazon EC2, Amazon VPC, and Amazon RDS.</li>
<li>The ability to record actions is limited to five actions per session.</li>
<li>The generated code requires further customization before being used in production.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="summary">Summary<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-console-to-code#summary" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do Summary" title="Bezpośredni link do Summary">​</a></h2>
<p>AWS Console-to-Code is an innovative tool that combines the ease of using the console with the power of Infrastructure-as-Code (IaC). It allows users to easily transition from prototyping to production, making it a valuable addition for developers and DevOps engineers.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Piotr Kmita</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/timon2013/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="amazon aws" term="amazon aws"/>
        <category label="amazon" term="amazon"/>
        <category label="ai" term="ai"/>
        <category label="aws" term="aws"/>
        <category label="cli" term="cli"/>
        <category label="code" term="code"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Q Developer Code Challenge]]></title>
        <id>https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-q-developer-code-challenge</id>
        <link href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-q-developer-code-challenge"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Q Developer Code Challenge]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="amazon-q-developer-code-challenge">Amazon Q Developer Code Challenge<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/amazon-q-developer-code-challenge#amazon-q-developer-code-challenge" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do Amazon Q Developer Code Challenge" title="Bezpośredni link do Amazon Q Developer Code Challenge">​</a></h3>
<p>The Amazon Q Developer Code Challenge, held at the 2024 AWS Summit, showcased a competition between two teams—one using Amazon Q Developer (an AI-powered assistant) and another coding manually.</p>
<p>The AI-assisted team excelled, leveraging Q Developer’s code suggestions to complete complex tasks faster. The challenge highlighted the transformative impact of generative AI in software development, allowing for more efficient coding, problem-solving, and collaboration. The event demonstrated how AI tools like Amazon Q Developer can enhance productivity in modern programming environments.</p>
<p>For more details, visit <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/devops/amazon-q-developer-code-challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Piotr Kmita</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/timon2013/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="amazon q" term="amazon q"/>
        <category label="amazon" term="amazon"/>
        <category label="ai" term="ai"/>
        <category label="gen ai" term="gen ai"/>
        <category label="challenge" term="challenge"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discover the Power of Amazon Q]]></title>
        <id>https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/discover-power-amazon-q</id>
        <link href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/discover-power-amazon-q"/>
        <updated>2024-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover the Power of Amazon Q]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="discover-the-power-of-amazon-q">Discover the Power of Amazon Q<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/discover-power-amazon-q#discover-the-power-of-amazon-q" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do Discover the Power of Amazon Q" title="Bezpośredni link do Discover the Power of Amazon Q">​</a></h3>
<p>Amazon has recently unveiled Amazon Q, a powerful generative AI assistant designed to revolutionize the way businesses operate. This innovative tool, now available, aims to streamline processes and increase productivity across various industries.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-amazon-q">What is Amazon Q?<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/discover-power-amazon-q#what-is-amazon-q" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do What is Amazon Q?" title="Bezpośredni link do What is Amazon Q?">​</a></h4>
<p>Amazon Q is an AI assistant that utilizes generative AI, leveraging advanced machine learning models to support a wide range of business applications. It offers advanced capabilities for automating tasks, providing insights, and enhancing decision-making processes. Whether you need to build custom AI applications or integrate AI into existing processes, Amazon Q provides a comprehensive solution.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="key-features">Key Features<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/discover-power-amazon-q#key-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do Key Features" title="Bezpośredni link do Key Features">​</a></h4>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Amazon Q Apps</strong>: This feature allows businesses to create AI-powered applications tailored to their specific needs. Users can build applications using natural language and approved data sources, making it easier to deploy generative AI solutions without deep technical expertise.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Integration with SageMaker Studio</strong>: Developers can now use Amazon Q within SageMaker Studio, benefiting from customized code suggestions and advanced productivity tools. This integration simplifies the development and deployment of AI models.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Advanced AI Capabilities</strong>: Amazon Q offers features such as personalized responses based on employee profiles, the ability to extract information from scanned PDFs and images, and new APIs for programmatic app management.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Security and Compliance</strong>: With a security-first approach, Amazon Q ensures that all AI interactions and data are handled with the highest standards of privacy and compliance, making it suitable for use in regulated industries.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-choose-amazon-q">Why Choose Amazon Q?<a href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/discover-power-amazon-q#why-choose-amazon-q" class="hash-link" aria-label="Bezpośredni link do Why Choose Amazon Q?" title="Bezpośredni link do Why Choose Amazon Q?">​</a></h4>
<p>Amazon Q stands out as a versatile and robust AI assistant that can be easily integrated into various business processes. Its ability to automate and enhance tasks saves time and resources, allowing employees to focus on more strategic activities. Moreover, its seamless integration with existing AWS tools and services ensures that businesses can leverage their current infrastructure to fully benefit from generative AI technology.</p>
<p>In summary, Amazon Q is not just an AI assistant; it is a comprehensive tool designed to drive innovation and efficiency in modern business environments. With its advanced features and user-friendly capabilities, Amazon Q is poised to become an invaluable asset for companies looking to harness the power of AI.</p>
<p>I personally use Amazon Q integrated with Visual Studio Code. It speeds up my scripting, although it can be somewhat annoying at times. If you're interested in using it in your environment, here is the official documentation: <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/toolkit-for-vscode/latest/userguide/welcome.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS Toolkit for Visual Studio Code</a>.</p>
<p>With this integration, you can increase your productivity and efficiency in daily programming tasks by utilizing advanced AI features directly in Visual Studio Code.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Piotr Kmita</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/timon2013/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="amazon q" term="amazon q"/>
        <category label="amazon" term="amazon"/>
        <category label="visual studio code" term="visual studio code"/>
        <category label="ai" term="ai"/>
        <category label="gen ai" term="gen ai"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/welcome</id>
        <link href="https://piotrkmita.cloud/en/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2024-05-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to my website! This is the first post on this blog, and hopefully not the last :)]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my website! This is the first post on this blog, and hopefully not the last :)</p>
<p>I decided to create a simple website that I won't have to spend a lot of time maintaining and managing. Previously, I mainly operated on the Wordpress system, but this time I opted for Docusaurus.io solution. This allows me to integrate with the Github environment and write posts using Markdown.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Piotr Kmita</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/timon2013/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="welcome" term="welcome"/>
        <category label="hello" term="hello"/>
        <category label="site" term="site"/>
        <category label="blog" term="blog"/>
    </entry>
</feed>